Guide to the Edwin Richard Weinerman Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Correspondence, 1945-1970; Series I; 8.5 linear feet (21 boxes)
  - Struthers, Robert Rolf (1), 1951 (Box 18, Folder 805)
  - Stubbs, Trawick Hamilton (2), 1951 (Box 18, Folder 805)
  - Suchman, Edward A.
    See: box 19, folder 868
  - Susser, Mervyn W., 1965-1966 (Box 18, Folder 806)
  - Sviridoff, Mitchell
    See: box 4, folder 164
  - Swanson, Jess N. (2), 1954 (Box 18, Folder 807)
  - Sweney, Barbara (2), 1967 (Box 18, Folder 807)
  - Switzer, John
    See: box 7, folder 270
  - T (22), 1947, 1950-1951, 1959, 1961-1964, 1967, 1969, undated (Box 18, Folder 808)
  - Taback, Matthew (2), 1951 (Box 18, Folder 809)
  - Talbot, Joseph Edward (1), 1946 (Box 18, Folder 809)
  - Talpers, Stanley
  - Taylor, R.G. (2), 1966 (Box 18, Folder 810)
  - Technical Education Research Center
    See: box 3, folder 110
  - Teilman, Mina (1), 1951 (Box 18, Folder 811)
  - Tepping, Morris (5), 1958, 1962 (Box 18, Folder 811)
  - Terris, Milton (28), 1947-1949 (Box 18, Folder 812)
  - Terris, Milton (35), 1950-1951 (Box 18, Folder 813)
  - Terris, Milton (27), 1952-1957 (Box 18, Folder 814)
  - Terris, Milton (25), 1958-1960, 1962-1965, 1968-1969 (Box 18, Folder 815)
  - Terris, Milton
  - Thomas, Addle (4), 1949 (Box 18, Folder 816)
  - Thomas, Bert Stanford (3), 1949, 1962 (Box 18, Folder 816)
  - Thomas, Elbert Duncan (1), 1949 (Box 18, Folder 817)
  - Thomas, F.
    See: box 10, folder 239
  - Thomas, Norman (3), 1956 (Box 18, Folder 817)
  - Thomas, Trevor (12), 1954-1956, 1958-1959, 1963 (Box 18, Folder 818)
  - Thompson, Douglas (4), 1965, 1968 (Box 18, Folder 819)
  - Thoms, Herbert (1), 1948 (Box 18, Folder 819)
  - Time (1), 1963 (Box 18, Folder 820)
  - Tirodkar, R.S. (1), 1951 (Box 18, Folder 820)
  - Tolins, Peter (2), 1960 (Box 18, Folder 821)
  - Tonkin, Thomas E. (5), 1951 (Box 18, Folder 821)
  - Toronto, University of
    See: box 9, folder 337
  - Torrence, Robert G. (1), 1965 (Box 18, Folder 822)
  - Torrens, Paul Roger (1), 1966 (Box 18, Folder 822)
  - Tougaloo College
    See: box 14, folder 608
  - Trichter, Benjamin (8), 1946, 1950-1952 (Box 19, Folder 823)
  - Truman, Stanley Roosevelt (2), 1951, undated (Box 19, Folder 824)
  - Trussell, Ray Elbert (12), 1951-1952, 1960, 1966 (Box 19, Folder 825)
  - Tolman, Edward C. (1), 1953 (Box 19, Folder 826)
  - Tulchinsky, Theodore H. (4), 1968-1970 (Box 19, Folder 826)
  - Tuli, Ram Lal (5), 1967 (Box 19, Folder 827)
  - Tulin, Maurice (2), 1966 (Box 19, Folder 828)
  - Tunley, Roul (2), 1966 (Box 19, Folder 828)
  - Tuntler, J.H. (4), 1950-1951 (Box 19, Folder 829)
  - Tuttle, Robert W. (2), 1961 (Box 19, Folder 830)
  - U (25), 1946, 1948-1949, 1951-1955, 1958, 1962-1963, 1965, 1967 (Box 19, Folder 831)
  - United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America, Local 586 (5), 1962 (Box 19, Folder 832)
  - United States Atomic Energy Commission (1), 1958 (Box 19, Folder 833)
  - United States Civil Service Commission (4), 1960, 1963 (Box 19, Folder 834)
  - United States Conference of City Health Officers (2), 1969-1970 (Box 19, Folder 835)
  - United States Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, National Center for Health Services Research and Development
    See: box 16, folder 706
  - United States Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, Public Health Service (2), 1963 (Box 19, Folder 836)
  - United States Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, Public Health Service
    See: box 14, folder 578
  - United States Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, Public Health Service, Division of Hospital and Medical Facilities
    See: box 9, folder 365 box 11, folder 445
  - United States Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, Public Health Service, Division of Research Grants
    See: box 11, folder 458
  - United States Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, Public Health Service, Office of the Surgeon General
    See: box 4, folder 138
  - United States Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, Public Health Service, Public Health Reports
    See: box 15, folder 649
  - United States Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, Welfare Administration
    See: box 18, folder 794
  - United States Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, White House Conference on Health
    See: box 1, folder 19
  - United States Department of Labor (1), 1955 (Box 19, Folder 837)
  - United States Department of State (1), 1959 (Box 19, Folder 838)
  - United States Treasury Department (5), 1947, 1962 (Box 19, Folder 839)
  - Unruh, Jesse (1), 1959 (Box 19, Folder 840)
  - V (5), 1950-1952, 1963, undated (Box 19, Folder 841)
  - Vallejo Unified School District, Department of Adult Education (8), 1949 (Box 19, Folder 842)
  - Van Goor, Robert E.
  - Van Goor, Robert E.
  - Vaughan, Henry Frieze (6), 1949, 1965-1966 (Box 19, Folder 843)
  - Vayda, Eugene (4), 1966 1969 (Box 19, Folder 844)
  - Venolia, A.W. (2), 1956 (Box 19, Folder 844)
  - Vernon, W.E. (3), 1949 (Box 19, Folder 845)
  - Vesely, J.
  - Veterans Administration
  - Vial, Don (5), 1960, 1966 (Box 19, Folder 846)
  - Vollan, Douglas Dee (1), undated (Box 19, Folder 847)
  - Voorhees, Tracy S.
  - Voorhis, Jerry
  - Vukmanovik, Cedomir (10), 1969 (Box 19, Folder 848)
  - W (32), 1946-1950, 1952, 1955 (Box 19, Folder 849)
  - Wagner, Carruth J. (1), 1965 (Box 19, Folder 850)
  - Wagner, Jocelyn (5), 1948-1949 (Box 19, Folder 851)
  - Wainfield, Benjamin (6), 1968 (Box 19, Folder 852)
  - Wainwright, Randy (3), 1968, undated (Box 19, Folder 852)
  - Wald, Florence S. (2), 1965 (Box 19, Folder 853)
  - Waldinger, Clara (2), 1949-1950 (Box 19)
  - Walker, James E.C. (19), 1962-1965 (Box 19, Folder 854)
  - Walker, James E.C. (4), 1966-1967 (Box 19, Folder 855)
  - Walker, Mildred F. (4), 1960-1961 (Box 19, Folder 856)
  - Wallace, J.D. (2), 1964 (Box 19, Folder 856)
  - Wallach, Laurie G. (2), 1969 (Box 19, Folder 857)
  - Walton, William Stanley (2), 1951-1952 (Box 19, Folder 857)
  - Ward, Paul D.
    See: box 4, folder 165
  - Warren, Stafford L. (9), 1949, 1952, 1954 (Box 19, Folder 858)
  - Washington Post (4), 1947 (Box 19, Folder 859)
  - Washington Report on the Medical Sciences (3), 1949, 1963 (Box 19, Folder 859)
  - Wasserbaugh, Claire (2), 1949 (Box 19, Folder 859)
  - Waterson, Rollen W.
  - Weber, Francis John (2), 1960 (Box 19, Folder 860)
  - Weekes, Francis (3), 1949 (Box 19, Folder 860)
  - Weeks, D.E. (1), 1969 (Box 19, Folder 860)
  - Weeks, Lewis E. (2), 1966 (Box 19, Folder 861)
  - Wehrle, Paul F. (2), 1969 (Box 19, Folder 861)
  - Weinerman, David T. (4), 1951, 1961-1962 (Box 19, Folder 862)
  - [Weinerman?], Mary (2), 1962 (Box 19, Folder 862)
  - Weinerman, Robert A. (1), 1962 (Box 19, Folder 863)
  - Weinerman, Shirley (2), 1946, 1961 (Box 19, Folder 863)
  - Weiskotten, H.G. (2), 1948 (Box 19, Folder 864)
  - Weissman, Art (2), 1947, 1950 (Box 19, Folder 865)
  - Wenkert, Walter (6), 1964 (Box 19, Folder 866)
  - Wertham, Fredric (3), 1949 (Box 19, Folder 867)
  - Wessel, Morris A. (3), 1962, 1964 (Box 19, Folder 867)
  - Wessen, Albert F. (2), 1969 (Box 19, Folder 868)
  - West Contra Costa County Community Welfare Council (1), 1961 (Box 19, Folder 869)
  - West Contra Costa County Mental Health Society (2), 1954, 1958 (Box 19, Folder 869)
  - "What's Your Opinion?" (television program) (1), 1953 (Box 19, Folder 870)
  - White, Kerr Lachlan (25), 1962-1966, 1968-1970 (Box 19, Folder 871)
  - Whitfield, L.K. (2), 1950 (Box 19, Folder 872)
  - Whitney, James G. (2), 1955-1956 (Box 19, Folder 872)
  - Wiggins, Walter Sproule (1), 1960 (Box 20, Folder 873)
  - Wilbur, Dwight L.
    See: box 4, folder 122
  - Wilder, Theodore Stanley (1), 1963 (Box 20, Folder 873)
  - Wilder, Theodore Stanley
  - Wilinsky, Charles Francis (25), 1949-1953 (Box 20, Folder 874)
  - Wilkins, George Franklin (2), 1951 (Box 20, Folder 875)
  - Wilkinson, Frank (11), 1954-1955, 1960, 1965, undated (Box 20, Folder 875)
  - Willard, Harold N.
  - Willard, William Robert (2), 1963 (Box 20, Folder 876)
  - Williams, Robert (2), 1963 (Box 20, Folder 877)
  - Williams, Robert
  - Williams, Robert S. (2), 1969 (Box 20, Folder 877)
  - Williams, T. Franklin (7), 1963, 1965-1966 (Box 20, Folder 878)
  - Wilner, Daniel M. (1), 1966 (Box 20, Folder 879)
  - Wilson, Charles C. (2), 1947 (Box 20, Folder 880)
  - Wilson, Glenn (7), 1955, 1959-1960, 1962 (Box 20, Folder 881)
  - Wilson, Glenn
  - Wilson, William S.
  - Windmiller, Marshall (5), 1960, 1962, 1964 (Box 20, Folder 882)
  - Winebrenner, John D.
  - Wing, Wilson Mumford (9), 1949-1950 (Box 20, Folder 883)
  - Winik, Irving (4), 1950-1951 (Box 20, Folder 884)
  - Winnett, Thomas (1), 1966 (Box 20, Folder 885)
  - Winquist, Paul Gordon (2), 1960 (Box 20, Folder 886)
  - Winslow, Charles-Edward Amory (4), 1952 (Box 20, Folder 887)
  - Winslow, William F. (2), 1967 (Box 20, Folder 888)
  - Wise, Harold (16), 1965-1966, 1968-1969 (Box 20, Folder 889)
  - Wolfe, Samuel (11), 1963-1964 (Box 20, Folder 890)
  - Wolffson, Joanne (1), 1954 (Box 20, Folder 891)
  - Wolffson, Sol Milton (10), 1951, 1957 (Box 20, Folder 891)
  - Woman's Home Companion
    See: box 5, folder 201
  - Woman's Medical College of Pennsylvania
    See: box 17, folder 752
  - Womer, Charles B. (2), 1968 (Box 20, Folder 892)
  - Woodcock, Leonard (3), 1956, 1961 (Box 20, Folder 893)
  - Woodhill, Joan (1), undated (Box 20, Folder 894)
  - Woods, Philip W. (2), 1950 (Box 20, Folder 894)
  - World Affairs Council of Northern California (5), 1949 (Box 20, Folder 895)
  - World Health Organization (28), 1950-1951, 1953, 1956 (Box 20, Folder 896)
  - World Health Organization (18), 1968-1970 (Box 20, Folder 897)
  - World Today Discussion Group (2), 1959 (Box 20, Folder 898)
  - World Wide Medical News Service (5), 1956 (Box 20, Folder 898)
  - Wright, John (2), 1967 (Box 20, Folder 899)
  - Wright, Philip B. (1), 1961 (Box 20, Folder 899)
  - Wright, Robert D. (3), 1956, 1969 (Box 20, Folder 899)
  - Wurzel, Lillian (5), 1950-1951, 1962 (Box 20, Folder 900)
  - Wyatt, Joseph L. (5), 1959-1961 (Box 20, Folder 901)
  - Y, Z (5), 1949, 1955, 1966, undated (Box 20, Folder 902)
  - Yale, Jeffrey F. (2), 1967 (Box 20, Folder 903)
  - Yale Journal of Biology and Medicine (4), 1963 (Box 20, Folder 904)
  - Yale-New Haven Hospital
    See: box 17, folder 774
  - The Yale Scientific Magazine (2), 1968 (Box 20, Folder 904)
  - Yankauer, Alfred (7), 1950, 1966 (Box 20, Folder 905)
  - Yedidia, Avram (22), 1952, 1962-1966, 1969 (Box 20, Folder 906)
  - Yedidia, Avram
    See: box 36, folder 203 See: box 37, folder 216 See: box 37, folder 211
  - Yerby, Alonzo Smythe (17), 1948, 1951-1952, 1954, 1961-1962, 1964-1965, 1968 (Box 20, Folder 907)
  - Yett, Donald E. (3), 1964, 1966 (Box 20, Folder 908)
  - Young, Edward Lorraine (12), 1948-1949, 1953-1954, 1963-1964 (Box 20, Folder 909)
  - Young, William R. (2), 1964 (Box 20, Folder 910)
  - Zappfe, Fred C.
    See: box 2, folder 45
  - Zeiter, Walter J.
  - Zetterberg, Steve (13), 1960-1962 (Box 20, Folder 911)
  - Zibit, Samuel (11), 1950, 1952-1953, 1956, 1960-1961 (Box 20, Folder 912)
  - Ziegler, Mark V. (3), 1946 (Box 20, Folder 913)
  - Ziferstein, Isidore (7), 1955, 1958 (Box 20, Folder 914)
  - Zimmerman, Kent A. (2), 1952 (Box 20, Folder 915)
  - Zola, Irving K. (4), 1968 (Box 20, Folder 916)
  - letters of concolence received after the death of Dr. and Mrs. Weinerman (54), 1970 (Box 20, Folder 917)
  - duplicate correspondence, A-C (Box 21, Folder 918)
    (Xerox copies filed in Series I)
  - duplicate correspondence, D-H (Box 21, Folder 919)
  - duplicate correspondence, I-O (Box 21, Folder 920)
  - duplicate correspondence, P-Z (Box 21, Folder 921)
  - unidentified correspondence (Box 21, Folder 922)
- Consultations, Projects, and Professional Assignments, 1943-1970; Series II; 12 linear feet (26 boxes, 1 carton)
  Scope and Contents
  The second series, CONSULTATIONS, PROJECTS, AND PROFESSIONAL ASSIGNMENTS, is divided into twenty-eight subsections. The subsections and their contents have been described in the introductory section of this register.
  - Farm Security Administration
    - unidentified correspondence, 1946-1947, undated (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - memoranda and notes re: FSA plans and programs, 1941, 1943-1944, 1946 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - memoranda and notes re: FSA plans and programs, 1946-1947 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - memoranda, and notes re: FSA plans and programs, undated (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - papers re: FSA plans and programs, 1939-1943 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - papers re: FSA plans and programs, 1944-1946, undated (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - memoranda and papers re: experimental rural health program, 1942-1945 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - reports of field trips by Weinerman to FSA Regions, 1946 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - testimony of American Veterans Committee on Wagner-Murray-Dingell Bill, 1946 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - testimony of U.S.D.A. on Wagner-Murray-Dingell Bill, 1946 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - FSA pamphlets (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - "Control of Poison Ivy" by E. R. Weinexman, 1945 (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - "Medical Care and Rural Life" by C.F. Brannan and E. R. Weinerman, 1946 (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - "Rural Prepayment Medical Care Plans and Public Health Agencies" by M. Ziegler, E.R. Weinerman, and M.I. Roemer, 1947 (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - addresses and articles on rural health problem and FSA programs, 1938, 1942, 1944, 1946, undated (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - government reports on the Farm Security Administration and experimental health programs, 1944, 1946 (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - misc. (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - United States Public Health Service
    - documents, letters re: Weinerman's U.S.P.H.S commission, 1946-1947, 1951 (Box 24, Folder 18)
    - memoranda re: U.S.P.H.S. plans and programs, 1947 (Box 24, Folder 19)
    - "Health Aspects of a Program for National Security" (report to the President's Advisory Commission on Universal Training), 1947 (Box 24, Folder 20)
    - "Health Aspects of a Program for National Security" (early drafts) (Box 24, Folder 21)
    - "Documents in Connection with the Appearance of Federal Security Administration Representatives before the President's Advisory Commission on Universal Training", 1947 (Box 24, Folder 22)
    - reports on universal training, 1947 (Box 24, Folder 23)
    - reports on health and education, undated (Box 24, Folder 24)
  - New York State Temporary Commission on the Need for a State University
    - background material and comments, 1947 (Box 24, Folder 25)
    - draft of memorandum on medical education, 1947 (Box 24, Folder 26)
    - Education for the Health Services (draft copy of a report to the commission), 1948 (Box 24, Folder 27)
    - Report of the Temporary Commission on the Need for a State University, 1948 (Box 24, Folder 28)
  - Boston Health Survey
    - background material and notes (Box 24, Folder 29)
    - "Report of a Survey of the Boston City Health Department" by E. R. Weinerman, 1948 (Box 24, Folder 30)
    - "Report of Health Division" by I. V. Hiscock and H. R. Leavell (pp. 1-144), 1949 (Box 25, Folder 31)
    - "Report of Health Division" by I. V. Hiscock and H. R. Leavell (pp. 145-206), 1949 (Box 25, Folder 32)
    - "Report of Hospital Division" by B. C. Mac Lean and A. W. Snoke (pp. 1-77), 1949 (Box 25, Folder 33)
    - "Report of Hospital Division" by B. C. Mac Lean and A. W. Snoke (pp. 78-161), 1949 (Box 25, Folder 34)
    - newspaper clippings and articles (Box 25, Folder 35)
  - Commission on the Organization of the Executive Branch of Government (Hoover Commission)
    - Correspondences:
      - Brassor, Francis P. (2), 1948 (Box 25, Folder 36)
      - Harrison, W. T. (2), 1948-1949 (Box 25, Folder 36)
      - Kline, Howard M. (15), 1948-1949 (Box 25, Folder 37)
      - Mitchell, Sidney Alexander (1), 1948 (Box 25, Folder 37)
      - Veterans Administration (3), 1948 (Box 25, Folder 38)
      - Vorhees, Tracy S. (1), 1949 (Box 25, Folder 38)
      - Report by the Committee on Federal Medical Services, 1948 (Box 25, Folder 39)
      - "Federal Health Activities and Programs" by H. M. Kline (pp. 1-139), 1948 (Box 25, Folder 40)
      - "Federal Health Activities and Programs" by H. M. Kline (pp. 140-217), 1948 (Box 25, Folder 41)
      - "Area Surveys" by M. E. DeBakey, M. Lapham, and E. R. Weinerman, 1948 (Box 26, Folder 42)
      - press release containing summary of the Task Force report on Federal Medical Services, 1948 (Box 26, Folder 43)
      - Task Force Report on Federal Medical Services, 1949 (Box 26, Folder 44)
      - Reorganization of Federal Medical Activities, 1949 (Box 26, Folder 45)
  - American Public Health Association, Subcommittee on Medical Care
    - minutes and notices re: statement on quality of medical care, 1947-1948, 1951, undated (Box 26, Folder 46)
    - "The Quality of Medical Care," outline and 1948 draft (Box 26, Folder 47)
    - The Quality of Medical Care in a National Health Program, 1949 Jan draft (Box 26, Folder 48)
    - The Quality of Medical Care in a National Health Program, 1949 Jan draft (Box 26, Folder 49)
    - The Quality of Medical Care in a National Health Program, 1949 Mar draft (Box 26, Folder 50)
    - The Quality of Medical Care in a National Health Program, 1949 May draft (Box 26, Folder 51)
    - The Quality of Medical Care in a National Health Program, 1949 printed copies (Box 26, Folder 52)
    - Standards of Quality in Organized Programs of Medical Care, 1951 Mar draft of The Quality of Medical Care in a National Health Program (Box 26, Folder 53)
    - The Quality of Medical Care, 1951 Mar draft of The Quality of Medical Care in a National Health Program (Box 26, Folder 54)
    - The Quality of Medical Care in Organized Health Programs, 1951 Sep draft of The Quality of Medical Care in a National Health Program (Box 26, Folder 55)
    - The Quality of Medical Care in Organized Health Programs, 1951 Sep draft (Box 26, Folder 56)
    - The Quality of Medical Care in Organized Health Programs, 1952 Jan draft (Box 27, Folder 57)
    - The Quality of Medical Care in Organized Health Programs, 1952 Mar (Box 27, Folder 58)
    - comments on The Quality of Medical Care…, 1948-1950 (Box 27, Folder 59)
    - comments on The Quality of Medical Care…, 1950 May-1951 (Box 27, Folder 60)
    - reviews and articles on The Quality of Medical Care…, 1950-1951 (Box 27, Folder 61)
  - Group Health Cooperative of Puget Sound
    - The Group Health Cooperative of Puget Sound; Report of a Study, 1950 draft (Box 27, Folder 62)
    - The Group Health Cooperative of Puget Sound; Report of a Study, 1950 printed copies (Box 27, Folder 63)
  - University of California School of Public Health
    - notes for Medical Care Seminars (P. H. 109A), 1949-1950 (Box 27, Folder 64)
    - notes for Medical Care Administration Seminars (P. H. 206A), 1949-1950 (Box 27, Folder 65)
    - notes for Medical Care Administration Seminars (P. H. 206A), 1949-1950 (Box 27, Folder 66)
    - notes for Medical Care Administration Seminars (P. H. 206B), 1950 (Box 28, Folder 67)
    - notes for Medical Sociology (p. H. 106), 1950? (Box 28, Folder 68-69)
    - report on medical care for the needy aged in Washington State by the University of California School of Public Health, 1950 (Box 28, Folder 70)
    - letters and papers re: loyalty oath controversy and Weinerman's resignation, 1949-1950 (Box 28, Folder 71)
  - Social Medicine in Western Europe
    - Social Medicine in Western Europe by E. R. Weinerman, 1951 (Box 28, Folder 72)
    - notes for Social Medicine in Western Europe, 1950 (Box 28, Folder 73)
    - itineraries, lists of names, etc., undated (Box 28, Folder 74)
    - World Health Organization certificates, papers, etc., 1950 (Box 28, Folder 75)
  - Permanente Health Plan
    - memoranda re: administration of Permanente Health Plan, 1950-1951 (Box 29, Folder 76)
    - objectives, principles, and standards of service for the Permanente Health Plan, undated (Box 29, Folder 77)
    - medical and hospital service agreements, undated (Box 29, Folder 78)
    - papers re: proposed statistical research program, 1951 (Box 29, Folder 79)
    - papers re: health coverage for the Retail Clerks Union, 1950 (Box 29, Folder 80)
    - notes and notices for the Permanente staff, 1948-1951, undated (Box 29, Folder 81)
    - "Educational Proceedings of the Permanente Hospitals", 1951 (Box 29, Folder 82)
    - "Report to the Board of Trustees of the Permanente Foundation on the several Health Activities in the San Francisco Bay Area Related to Their Jurisdiction", 1948 (Box 29, Folder 83)
    - articles, brochures, and pamphlets about Permanente (Box 29, Folder 84)
    - "The Permanente Health Plan" by E. R. Weinerman, 1951 (Box 29, Folder 85)
    - memoranda and papers re: Weineriman's: resignation from Permanente, 1951 (Box 29, Folder 86)
  - Hawaiian Sugar and Pineapple Workers Union Survey
    - Correspondence:
      - American Journal of Public Health (3), 1952 (Box 29, Folder 87)
      - Arnold, Harry Loren (11), 1952 (Box 29, Folder 87)
      - Beeston, Marion (1), 1952 (Box 29, Folder 88)
      - Bernstein, Leo (2), 1951-1952 (Box 29, Folder 88)
      - Bradfield, V. F. (1), 1952 (Box 29, Folder 88)
      - Burns, C. E. S (1), 1952 (Box 29, Folder 88)
      - Fairley, Lincoln (7), 1951-1952 (Box 29, Folder 89)
      - Fassoth, John (2), 1952 (Box 29, Folder 90)
      - Fox, Morris G. (3), 1952 (Box 29, Folder 90)
      - Hall, Jack W. (14), 1951-1953 (Box 29, Folder 91)
      - Hawaii Medical Journal (5), 1952-1953 (Box 29, Folder 91)
      - International Lonshoremen's and Warehousemen's Union (4), 1951-1952, 1954 (Box 29, Folder 92)
      - Journal of the American Medical Association (2), 1952 (Box 29, Folder 92)
      - Kreps, Theodora C. (12), 1952 (Box 29, Folder 93)
      - Larsen, Nils Paul (11), 1952 (Box 29, Folder 94)
      - Lee, Richard Kui Chi (7), 1952 (Box 29, Folder 94)
      - McLand, L, S. (1), 1952 (Box 29, Folder 95)
      - Moir, John T. (1), 1952 (Box 29, Folder 95)
      - Mountain, H. A. (1), 1952 (Box 29, Folder 95)
      - Orrick, James N. (1), 1952 (Box 29, Folder 95)
      - Ramsey, John F. (1), 1952 (Box 29, Folder 96)
      - Richardson, Robert (1), 1952 (Box 29, Folder 96)
      - Salz, Andrew (6), 1951-1953 (Box 29, Folder 96)
      - Shimizu, Mitsuo (1), 1952 (Box 29, Folder 97)
      - Steuermann, Nicholas (4), 1952-1953 (Box 29, Folder 97)
      - Tester, K. B. (1), 1952 (Box 29, Folder 98)
      - Wallis, Sam R. (1), 1952 (Box 29, Folder 98)
      - Wilbar, Charles (1), 1952 (Box 29, Folder 98)
      - Winslow, C.-E. A. (Box 29, Folder 98)
        General
        See: box 1, folder 30
      - Unidentified (1), 1952 (Box 29, Folder 98)
    - "Preliminary and, Summary Report on Medical Survey of Territory of Hawaii" by E. R. Weinerman, 1952 (Box 30, Folder 99)
    - "Medical Care in the Territory of Hawaii" by E. R. Weinerman, 1952 (Box 30, Folder 100)
    - "Medical Care in the Territory of Hawaii", 1952 (Box 30, Folder 101-102)
    - "Medical Care on the Sugar Plantation" by E. R. Weinerman, 1952 (Box 30, Folder 103)
    - "Public Health and Medical Care in Hawaii" by E. R. Weinerman (early draft), 1953 (Box 30, Folder 104)
    - "Public Health and Medical Care in Hawaii", 1953 (Box 30, Folder 105)
    - editorial attack in Plantation Health and Weinerman's reply, 1952 (Box 30, Folder 106)
    - newspaper articles and clippings, radio transcripts, and misc. (Box 30, Folder 107)
  - Family Health Record Study
    - outline for "Methodology" of the Family Health Record Study, undated (Box 30, Folder 108)
    - "Methodology of a Family Health Study" by C. F. Muller, A. Waybur, and E. R. Weinerman, 1951 (Box 30, Folder 109)
    - "Methodology" of the Family Health Record Study by E. R. Weinerman, C. F. Muller, and J. Yerushalmy, 1951 (Box 30, Folder 110)